Erick Garcia Flores

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

A passionate software developer with 3+ years of experience, I hope to work with a company that aligns with my values and interests as well as have a challenging and rewarding programming position. My main interests are UX (User design), Web Development, writing high quality easy to maintain code. My strongest asset by far is that I am an agile learner. If you want to learn more about the rest of my projects and my hobbies visit my website and extended resume!



me@erick-garcia.com



Seattle, WA, United States



linkedin.com/in/garciaErickCs

+1 9152400350



erick-garcia.com/resources/resume-extended.pdf



github.com/garciaErick

WORK EXPERIENCE

Prime Air Engineer **Amazon Corporation**

08/2020 - Present

Seattle, WA

Changing the lives of customers by building a package delivering infrastructure on the air through drones.

- Worked on software validators to get Federal Aviation Administration approval, involving functional requirement validation, physics of the drone, etc.
- Developed from start to finish the infrastructure for our services involving (CDK, pipelines, integration testing, EC2 Services, metrics, alarms, etc)

Contact: Rene Mader - rpmader@amazon.com

Full-stack Angular Developer **Applied Materials**

06/2019 - Present

Worked with a remote team in the Semiconductor industry on a ETL and data analysis tool. Technologies used are Angular, Java, and virtualization.

Achievements/Tasks

- Migrated our data analysis legacy tool to Angular 8 employing latest industry standards which highly improved the quality of the code base
- Created infrastructure for unit testing and code review and enforced them on the front-end team through positive reinforcement and mentorship

Contact: Alex Pai - alex_pai@amat.com

Service Information Developer II DXC Technology

03/2018 - 05/2019

Develop, maintain and test healthcare portals (MMIS Applications). Understand the business and technical aspect of the healthcare industry. Fixing security exploits in most of healthcare portals in the US

Contact: Oswaldo Perez - oswaldo.perez@dxc.com

Product Platform V&V Intern **Intel Corporation**

Hillsboro, OR

Verification and validation on processors with the following technologies: WinForms UX Design, C# WCF protocols, unit testing and mock testing.

Contact: Tristan Hanson - tristan.hanson@intel.com

Graduate Research Assistant The University of Texas at El Paso 🗷

01/2014 - 03/2018

El Paso, TX

Performing research in the fields of Semantic Web, Data Mining, and Ontologies.

Contact: Doctor Natalia Villanueva - nvillanuevarosales@utep.edu

EDUCATION

Master of Science - Software Engineering The University of Texas at El Paso

2017 - 2018 3.44

Cyber secure systems specialization

 The practicum project consisted of a plugin architecture add on for IDA a disassembler and debugger, that enhanced the functionality and it is currently used by cyber security development teams in Fort Bliss

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science The University of Texas at El Paso

2014 - 2016 3.33

Minor

Mathematics

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

Java, C#, PHP, Python, Typescript, MySQL, SPARQL, Oracle, MongoDB, OWL (Ontology)

Methodologies

SOLID (Clean code), Agile Development & SCRUM, User-first design, Testdriven development

Tools & Environments

Visual Studio, IntelliJ, Command line, Hyper-V and VMWare, Docker & Kubernetes, GIT & TFS, Vim > Emacs

Patterns

MVC, MVVM, Singleton, Factory

LANGUAGES

English Spanish 日本語 Japanese